<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="chloevoyer.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="chloevoyer.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-10-09T16:37:35+00:00</updated><id>chloevoyer.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><entry><title type="html">Screening Tips: Red Flags Edition 🚩</title><link href="chloevoyer.com/blog/2024/screening-tips/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Screening Tips: Red Flags Edition 🚩"/><published>2024-10-07T11:12:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-07T11:12:00+00:00</updated><id>chloevoyer.com/blog/2024/screening-tips</id><content type="html" xml:base="chloevoyer.com/blog/2024/screening-tips/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="tips-for-quickly-identifying-abstracts-to-exclude">Tips for Quickly Identifying Abstracts to Exclude</h3> <p>When conducting a literature review, I start by identifying the quickest elements to exclude an article. This approach allows me to streamline the process and focus on the most relevant studies.</p> <h4 id="participant-criteria">Participant Criteria</h4> <p>The participant criteria are typically the easiest elements to locate. I search for sections labeled <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Methods</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Participants</code>, or <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Sample</code>, and occasionally in <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Objectives/Aim</code>. This section usually appears right after the introduction and often provides key figures, such as sample size or mean age, within the first one or two sentences of the abstract.</p> <p>This is also where you can verify whether diagnostic or age criteria are met, especially when distinguishing between children and adults.</p> <p>If your platform allows it (e.g., Rayyan, COVIDENCE), use highlighting features to search for inclusion/exclusion criteria keywords. This technique can significantly speed up your screening process!</p> <h4 id="conference-proceedings">Conference Proceedings</h4> <p>Be cautious of articles with conference details, such as:</p> <blockquote> <p>[…] 60th Annual National Conference of All India Occupational Therapists Association (AIOTA), (OTICON 2023), February 2-5, 2023.</p> </blockquote> <p>Look for keywords like <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">proceedings</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">conference</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">symposium</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">meeting</code>, or <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">workshop</code>, along with abbreviations like <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Conf</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Symp</code>, or <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Proc</code>, usually followed by a location and date. For example, <em>Proceedings of the 23rd International Conference on…</em> or <em>Symposium on XYZ, held in…</em> indicate conference proceedings.</p> <p>If the title starts with a session number (e.g., <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">T50</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">S49</code>), it’s often an abstract submitted for a conference presentation and should be excluded due to lack of peer review.</p> <h4 id="dissertations-and-theses">Dissertations and Theses</h4> <p>Identify keywords such as <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">dissertation</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">thesis</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Ph.D.</code>, or <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">doctoral</code>. For example, <em>Master’s Thesis, University of…</em> or <em>Ph.D. Dissertation, Department of…</em> indicate non-peer-reviewed material.</p> <h4 id="books-and-book-chapters">Books and Book Chapters</h4> <p>Look for terms like <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">chapter</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">section</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">handbook</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">guide</code>, or <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">edited by</code>. Examples include <em>Chapter 4 in…</em> or <em>Handbook of Cognitive Science…</em></p> <p>Most books will not have a DOI but will have an ISSN or ISBN number (unless very recent). Be cautious of overly brief and non-descriptive titles, as journals typically require more detailed titles for articles.</p> <h4 id="non-peer-reviewed-sources">Non-Peer-Reviewed Sources</h4> <p>Exclude materials that are labeled as <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">editorial</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">opinion</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">commentary</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">letter to the editor</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">perspective</code>, or <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">review</code> (if not systematic). Examples include <em>Editorial: The Future of…</em> or <em>Letter to the Editor regarding…</em> Non-peer-reviewed sources can also include manuals, guides, resource lists, reports, and handbooks.</p> <h4 id="news-articles-and-magazine-pieces">News Articles and Magazine Pieces</h4> <p>Identify articles published in newspapers, magazines, or other media outlets. Examples include <em>Published in The New York Times</em> or <em>Article in Time Magazine…</em> Articles lacking a DOI (unless they are books) are red flags for exclusion.</p> <h4 id="language-and-accessibility">Language and Accessibility</h4> <p>Exclude abstracts in languages not covered by your review unless translation is feasible. For instance, if the review includes only English-language studies, any Spanish publications should be excluded.</p> <h4 id="publication-status">Publication Status</h4> <p>Exclude abstracts marked as <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">in press</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">forthcoming</code>, or <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">submitted</code>. For example, <em>Article in press</em> or <em>Forthcoming in Journal of…</em> indicates that the study has not yet been published.</p> <p>Additionally, if the abstract is written in the future tense (e.g., <em>we will recruit 50 participants</em>) or includes the word <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">protocol</code>, it should be excluded, as it indicates that data collection has not occurred. Absence of quantitative data in the abstract is also a good indicator for exclusion, except for qualitative studies (e.g., <em>M</em> = 39.9, <em>SD</em> = 5.9).</p> <h4 id="year-of-publication">Year of Publication</h4> <p>Filter out articles published outside the specified date range of your review. For example, exclude studies published in 1999 if your review covers 2000-2023.</p> <h4 id="non-empirical-studies">Non-Empirical Studies</h4> <p>Exclude theoretical papers, narrative reviews, or non-empirical discussions. Examples include <em>A theoretical exploration of…</em> or <em>Narrative review of…</em></p> <h4 id="case-studies">Case Studies</h4> <p>If an abstract mentions only one participant or includes phrases like <em>the story of…</em> or <em>vignette</em>, it is likely a case study, which should be excluded.</p> <h4 id="recommended-citation">Recommended Citation</h4> <p>Finally, reviewing the recommended citation at the end of an article can provide additional information that may help you determine whether to exclude it, especially if you are familiar with citation formatting styles.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="research"/><category term="literature-review"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tips for quickly identifying abstracts to exclude]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fitness Tracker | Notion Template</title><link href="chloevoyer.com/blog/2024/fitness-tracker-notion-template/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fitness Tracker | Notion Template"/><published>2024-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>chloevoyer.com/blog/2024/fitness-tracker--notion-template</id><content type="html" xml:base="chloevoyer.com/blog/2024/fitness-tracker-notion-template/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Import Garmin activities into Notion database. | Discover new ways to use Notion across work and life.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Studentships - Chloé Voyer — Mental Health Research Canada</title><link href="chloevoyer.com/blog/2024/2024-studentships-chlo-voyer-mental-health-research-canada/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Studentships - Chloé Voyer — Mental Health Research Canada"/><published>2024-04-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-04-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>chloevoyer.com/blog/2024/2024-studentships---chlo-voyer--mental-health-research-canada</id><content type="html" xml:base="chloevoyer.com/blog/2024/2024-studentships-chlo-voyer-mental-health-research-canada/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry></feed>